(Let's Go to My House)
Nice to see you all.
It's been a while.
- Nice to see you. - It's been a while.
I heard you found a new place.
Yes. I found a nice house.
- You moved? - Yes.
- Finally. - Yes, finally.
You sound like someone else.
(Chattering)
- Yes, my voice is hoarse. - You...
- Is it because of the World Cup? - Yes.
I was trying to outperform Bae Seong Jae.
(Joking)
- You can't, though. - I can't.
He's an expert.
I don't think you should talk.
I should.
- You found a new place. I should. - That's right.
Or we can keep the conversation going. You can rest.
What should I do then? Dance?
I'll do something at least.
(I'll do my share of the work.)
Let's check out his new house.
I can't wait to see it.
(The First Meeting Is Difficult)
"I'm grateful that it's not raining today."
You're still keeping up with your gratitude journal.
I can't believe you're still doing your gratitude journal.
"Before..."
"entering the new house,"
"I should..."
"calm myself down."
(Before entering the new house, I should calm myself down.)
- Is this the moving day? - Yes.
I won't be able to see the green leaves anymore.
I'm moving out of my old place where I lived for two years.
I found a new home for myself.
- So I'm moving today. - You're moving today.
(Last time, he looked into loans to move to a new place.)
(Kang Yong excitedly checked out different houses.)
You know what?
(You can't act all excited in front of realtors.)
Right. He was so excited in front of the realtors back then.
(Hyun Moo lectured him out of concern for him.)
(Knocking)
(This is nice.)
(What's nice about it?)
(Gosh, the elevator is opening.)
- Of course. - All elevators open.
- It'd be weird if they didn't. - I dreamed of having an elevator.
(Kang Yong, do you think you can find a new place?)
After that day,
I visited four more real estate agencies.
I looked at ten more houses.
(Kang Yong found a new place after all his effort.)
You lived there for two years.
Yes. I matured my lease before I moved out.
I have time.
(He writes his journal on the moving day.)
(But he hasn't packed his things in the bathroom yet.)
(His belongings haven't been packed either.)
- It's your moving day. - It's your...
- moving day. - You haven't packed anything.
(There's a pile of things to take care of.)
You didn't pack anything yet.
"The new house..."
You shouldn't be writing your journal now.
This is my last day here.
(I should start packing now.)
First of all,
I should start with my clothes.
I've already moved about ten times.
I think it won't take long to move.
Actually, I know some tips about packing up my things.
Besides, going up and down three flights of stairs is nothing.
I'm still young. So it won't be a problem.
(Kang Yong feels confident about packing.)
(Messily rolling his clothes)
If you roll them like that, you can't pack a lot of clothes.
- Right. - You can't pack a lot of clothes.
(Startled)
I thought an old guy was joining us.
It's like he traveled 20 years into the future.
Hyun Moo, it must be your voice.
You sound really wise.
- It's like... - It's like an elder is talking.
You know the master in the movie, "Kung Fu Panda?"
- You sound more trustworthy. - That's good.
- My words are wise. - It's like he's enlightened.
- It's like we shouldn't oppose him. - Right.
(Kang Yong is still packing his things.)
(Ringing)
"I just confirmed that your deposit has been returned."
Okay.
You got it back.
I just have to move into my new place.
- You must've been excited. - I bet it was fun.
Moving days are exciting.
I got this from my senior.
(I have memories about this book.)
I should bring it for the decor.
It's right here.
(Finding another item of nostalgia)
I found the pedals.
You had a piano?
I tried to take up the piano during COVID-19...
because we weren't allowed to gather.
I only played it once. After that...
- You're just like me. - Right.
I had it in the storage for six years.
I was trying to sell it through an app,
but I didn't have the pedals.
- I posted it, but couldn't sell it. - You didn't have the pedals either.
Are you your role model?
I found them on the moving day.
"MBC Basic Work Competency Assessment."
Gosh, this is crazy.
I studied to get into MBC in this house.
I have a lot of memories studying to get into MBC there.
So I won't be able to forget that house.
Luckily, your two years in the house have been all good.
Right.
The house must have good energy.
- Right. - Some houses have good energy.
I shouldn't.
Will it work?
(He gets a call when he's packing up.)
- Hello. - Hello.
- Hi. - Yes.
This is the cleaning crew captain.
- The cleaning crew? - Yes.
- Do you know the passcode? - Right.
I'll give you the passcode. Wait.
Were you able to get in?
No. Because we couldn't get in...
He just asked you for the passcode.
I was all over the place that day.
You don't want the home appliances like the fridge...
or the washing machine to be cleaned, right?
I thought it was included in the package.
- No, it's charged separately. - Is that so?
- That would cost extra. - Then...
- Right. - Then you don't have to clean them.
Okay. I got it.
Call me if you need anything else.
- Okay. - Okay.
(He finishes the phone call with the cleaning crew.)
(He gets another call.)
Hello, sir.
- Hello. - Hello.
- I'm on my way. - Yes.
It looks like I'll arrive...
- I called a mover. - at 2:05pm.
- I see. - I'll see you in a bit.
Okay.
I'm almost done.
Why did I buy this? I barely played it. Seriously.
I should take it with me. What could I do?
Give it to Hue.
The keyboard was working.
Sell all the keyboards to Hue.
All right.
(I should take this big table with me too.)
It's amazing that we always end up with more things.
I didn't know I had that much stuff in the balcony.
If you didn't use them there,
you wouldn't use them for the next two years either.
- Right. - That's so true.
- I haven't touched them yet. - I bet.
- Once you don't, you never do. - Never.
(Gosh, that old guy...)
(He's in front of the shoe closet.)
- Will they fit? - He has a lot of stuff.
- He's got a lot of shoes. - I need to be smart.
I saw this tip on social media.
They said packing shoes in a suitcase made things easier.
- Boxes would've been better. - Right.
- Or just plastic bags. - Yes.
I could fit only eight pairs in it.
- It's so inefficient. - It is.
(He busily packs his things in the bathroom.)
(A pile of kitchen items)
- You have so much stuff. - The kitchen... The shelves...
You have so much stuff.
Why do I have so much stuff?
There's no end.
Why do you have so much stuff? What do you do in the house?
He's here.
Hello.
- Hey. - Yes.
- I'm downstairs. - Yes.
But the thing is, I'm not done...
- packing my things yet. - I see.
We can do it together.
- Okay. - Could you come down for a second?
- I see. - Okay.
They pack things really fast.
My gosh.
(Rushing)
- Hello. - Hello.
(The mover has arrived.)
I bet he's really good at his job.
- He's got toned muscles. Right? - Yes.
(He climbs up 3 flights of stairs with the mover to his unit.)
- So you're moving everything here. - That's right.
- Then... - I boxed up some things.
- let's load the boxes... - Yes.
- you already packed. - Okay.
- After that, let's use my boxes... - Okay.
- to pack the rest. - Oh, we're using your boxes?
- Of course. - Thank you.
Today was the first time I got help from the movers...
to pack my things.
The package with partial packing assistance was quite expensive.
It cost 170 dollars.
It costs as much as a month's rent at my new place.
So I wanted to save up as much money as possible.
And I'm young and strong too.
I only needed partial assistance to pack.
I mean, I'm healthy too.
I believed in my abilities.
I thought it'd be too much to do it on my own.
But I thought getting the partial package would be okay.
You did it on your own before?
I did everything on my own. I even rented a truck.
You're so frugal.
(How frugal he is.)
Thank you.
- This old man approves. - Okay.
You're frugal.
Let's start with this box.
- I'll carry these two. - Okay.
- You see those boxes you packed? - Okay.
- Bring them one at a time. - One? Okay.
Those boxes aren't light at all.
His grip is different.
Right. And he crossed the boxes too.
- He knows what to do. - Yes.
(This young and strong guy will begin too.)
Yes, show us what you got.
Gosh, this is so heavy.
(Trying again)
(Inhaling sharply)
You have no idea what to do.
It was really heavy.
Gosh, it's the heaviest one.
You said you were young.
I'm young and strong too.
Do you miss your youth?
I used to be young once.
(Teary-eyed)
(Exhaling)
It's heavy, right?
You can just put that on the truck.
How do you carry two at once?
He dropped them off and is already going up.
(Struggling)
(He moves one box laboriously.)
He just moved one box.
(Lifting two boxes again)
- They were so heavy. - Just put that...
- Okay. - on the floor on the side.
(Securing the path for the mover's safety)
(He's amazing.)
(Breathing hard)
(Sighing)
(He's exhausted after moving one box.)
Why are you so tired after moving only one box?
I used a lot of my energy beforehand to pack my things.
- You're stalling. - Right.
(Scolding)
He rolled up his sleeves five times.
He didn't grab the box in one go.
"My gosh. This is heavy."
- He keeps complaining. - He's taking too long.
If you keep stalling like that,
movers would comment on that.
A long time ago, an old guy helped me move.
He said, "Are you trying to get this old man to pass out?"
He kept saying that.
He kept scolding me like that.
(While he's regrouping to roll up his sleeves, )
(the mover comes back quickly.)
(Startled)
(Lifting)
Let's go. I can do this.
There you go.
You got this.
I felt bad that I only carried one box down.
- So I tried carrying two. - Right.
Yes.
I've got to do this.
Let's go.
(Exhaling)
It would've been harder...
- without the elevator. - Right.
If there had been an elevator,
- you could've just put them in it. - Right.
(Sweating profusely after going up and down the stairs)
Your whole body is going to ache after this.
(Pulling up)
- This is heavy. - Okay.
Gosh, he just...
Seriously.
It looked so light in his hands.
(Surprised)
This is tough, isn't it?
Not having an elevator is huge.
(Panting)
Before packing, it doesn't look like you have a lot of stuff.
Seriously.
Once you start packing, there's no end. It's always like that.
It's like that for everyone, right?
- Other people... - He overtook Kang Yong.
It's hard to overtake someone on stairs.
(Impressed)
Let's bring down one box each.
(He follows his lead and carries the box.)
He told me what to do.
(He's carrying two boxes at once.)
My gosh. That's...
I would've given up moving...
without his help.
He had to keep going up and down three flights of stairs.
Carrying one box was heavy enough.
But he carried two boxes on his back.
He was like the Almighty.
He came to save me.
He got things done so fast.
I choked up a bit. I was incredibly grateful.
(I choked up out of gratitude.)
(He's working hard with every ounce of his energy just like the mover.)
Thinking of the old days when I did everything on my own...
made me realize how reckless I had been.
I can't do this alone now.
(Lifting hard)
(The truck is full.)
Gosh, the truck is full.
You have a lot of stuff.
(Soaked in sweat)
(Grabbing)
(Packing up the empty bottles)
Why are you taking the bottles?
They're bottles of expensive wine.
I took them home after work get-togethers.
I wanted to use them for decor.
They're valuable.
- For home decor? - I put them in my car. Yes.
Your new place will get cluttered pretty fast if you take them all.
It's odd. But you can't help...
but bring all of your things when you move.
They looked valuable to me.
I might find use for them in the new house.
- But you wouldn't notice them gone. - Right.
- Someone should get rid of them. - But you wouldn't notice that.
(He's indeed experienced.)
- His wisdom is on another level. - Right.
- I've gone through everything. - That...
(Just wait until you turn my age.)
(Carefully storing the empty bottles in his car)
The empty bottles...
I want to throw them out.
Hey, take the empty bottles to the district office.
(You're going to my new place, not the district office.)
This is a lot now that we loaded everything, right?
This is a lot of stuff.
- That's all my stuff. - That is a lot of stuff.
You do have a lot of stuff.
- I didn't know it'd be that much. - You do have a lot of things.
You do.
- I have to buy some trash bags... - Okay.
- and clean the house. - Okay.
- Take your time driving there. - Okay.
- I'll text you the passcode. - Okay.
- Please rest until I get there. - Okay.
- Then let's move them together. - Sure.
- I'll try to clean fast. - Okay.
But if you get there a bit late, he'll have moved everything by then.
That's why I told him many times...
- not to do that. - Right.
(Laughing)
(He comes back home to clean up one last time.)
(Grabbing)
(Messy)
(Let's clean up quickly.)
(He's doing the final sweep of the house.)
Gosh, my back hurts.
I don't even know how I got through packing everything.
(Lifting)
It must feel a bit sad.
Right here.
- It's 3.79 dollars. - Okay.
- He came to check the gas meter. - To settle the bill.
They calculate the meter on the moving day for the bill.
- He came for the payment. - I see.
I got the deposit.
Now, I have to settle the balance.
I got the deposit back...
and wired it to the landlord of my new place.
Isn't that a bit sad?
- Right. - It's not your money.
It only passes through your bank account.
It passes through. It was just there for a second.
There are so many things to do...
- when you move. - There were more things to handle.
(A busy moving day)
- Hey. - I'll throw them out and go.
- Did the truck leave? - Pardon?
Did the truck leave?
He's the landlord. He lives upstairs.
- I see. He lives upstairs? - Yes, he does.
(The landlord came down to say goodbye.)
The balcony was always like that.
Did anything break?
- No. - Nothing?
This is a clock from my company.
- A clock? - Yes.
- That's... - That was good.
It's a modern clock.
It's for you. It's from MBC.
- It's a silent clock. - Thank you.
- Sure. It's for you. - The house...
- I'll throw them out and go. - Okay.
Take care.
I'm leaving.
Bye.
- All right. Let's go. - He must feel happy and sad.
It looks like he's ready to move on.
People usually take a long look around...
- before leaving. Right? - That's true.
He came back.
- Leaving right away like that... - Right.
Made me feel a bit sad.
- Of course, it's sad. - Exactly.
- I'd never be able to come back. - Right.
(Kang Yong looks around the house one more time.)
Gosh, it was such a strange feeling.
- Earlier today, - Bye.
The house looked smaller without my things in there.
With my things inside, the house looked bigger.
But without them, the house looked...
I mean, I lived my life...
in this small, precious house.
I practiced for the job interview and commentating on sports games.
I ate and exercised in there. I did all kinds of things.
I had become attached to the house.
I'd think about this house a lot.
It was the first house I had gotten this attached to.
I mean it.
Goodbye, my lover.
(Checking the fridge)
(Tapping)
I'm leaving.
I had a good life here. Let me take a selfie.
I'm going.
Goodbye. Take care.
(I'm going. Goodbye.)
Well done.
(Taking one last photo of the building)
Let's get going.
(He heads to his new place now.)
This is really my last time here now.
My gosh. It's my last day here. I won't come back here.
Take care. Bye.
(He starts humming as soon as he leaves his old house.)
You'd forget the old place by the evening...
as if it were a dream...
- Right. - once you get to the new place.
- That's so true. - That's how we are.
- You'd completely forget it. - Yes.
Great. I'll be living in Gangnam.
- Gangnam? - Gangnam?
I mean it as the south of the river.
- Then Mokpo is Gangnam too. - Yes. That'd be Gangnam too.
- That's true. - I'm going to my new place...
which is near my work.
I'm almost there.
"Mok-dong Apartment."
(His destination is Mok-dong?)
I'm heading to Yangcheon-gu.
Turn here.
Hello, kids.
I'll be your neighbor.
Great.
(He arrives with excitement.)
He's already here.
The mover is already at the new place.
(This is great.)
I'm living near Sinmokdong Station.
It's super close to the station.
I can be at work in 10 to 15 minutes if there's no traffic by car.
Given the distance, the accessibility to work is great.
And the Han River is near my house.
I can easily go for a jog and exercise there.
It's a great place with everything nearby.
Instant rice.
And cash. Let's see.
Okay.
(Okay. Let's go.)
Let's go.
Gosh, there's an elevator.
I love it.
There's an elevator.
(There's an elevator in the building.)
(His heart is full.)
(He quickly gets into the elevator he's grateful for.)
I should enter with cash.
(He gets ready to enter the new home with instant rice.)
Is this the unit?
Okay.
(Opening)
I should bring in the instant rice first.
All good.
(I should bring in the instant rice first.)
Why did you toss in the rice?
When you move to a new place,
you carry a rice cooker inside first...
- Right. - for good luck.
But I didn't have a rice cooker. So I replaced it with instant rice.
I was told to bring in makgeolli first.
I guess it's different.
People bring in makgeolli or red beans.
- Right. - To drive out spirits?
(He finally walks into his new place.)
Gosh, it smells...
(A clean new home for Kang Yong)
It looks nice and neat.
It's well-lit too.
It's a one-bedroom studio.
It's so spacious.
(Even his bathroom is quite big.)
I love having a window in the bathroom.
It helps remove moisture.
Windows are essential.
I like that there's a washing machine.
- I see. This is... - Oh, I see.
- There's a balcony. - This is nice.
This was a major deciding factor in choosing this place.
- There's an outdoor balcony. - A balcony. Right.
I don't want to go out for drinks.
I can have beer or wine alone out in the balcony.
I can look at the view.
The balconies are often the deciding factor for many people.
- But people rarely use it. - Right.
- They'd never go out there. - I didn't use it once after moving.
Besides, it doesn't have a roof.
- You have one more place to clean. - Right.
The balcony will get caked with dirt.
- Dirt comes in when you open it. - Right.
It's too small for you to sit out there.
You'll probably go out there fewer than 30 times.
- I was going to... - But the view is unobstructed.
- Right. - The view is great, though.
(Checking out the bedroom instead of the unobstructed view)
I can't believe I have a bed. This is crazy.
Gosh, there's a closet too.
(But the house is already furnished.)
I'm really grateful. The previous tenant...
left the bed, the closet, the table in the living room,
and the computer desk.
For free?
I saved up a lot of money.
- I said I'd be happy to take them. - That's great.
The security deposit is 200,000 dollars.
The monthly rent is 150 dollars. It's a partial deposit-based house.
I got a 100,000-dollar loan from a bank.
I took out a 20,000-dollar loan from my company.
So my loans are 120,000 dollars.
I pay 290 dollars every month to the bank for the loan.
As for the loan from my company,
I'm amortizing it.
I have to pay back about 600 dollars every month.
So I'm paying 900 dollars every month.
- That's a lot of money. - That's how much I pay a month.
Nine hundred dollars is a hefty amount.
Seriously. That kind of money for office workers...
- It's not easy. - He has to be on a tight budget.
What about your car? Any expenses there?
- It was a used car. - I see.
- You bought it with cash. - I only have to cover...
- the gas for it. - I see.
After two years,
I can lower the interest rate of the loan...
from my company.
So I'll wait two years...
and then change it to another plan with a lower rate.
So I can reduce my expenses.
So I'm paying 900 dollars...
every month.
Including the rent, I have to pay 1,050 dollars.
The prices...
at the MBC cafeteria are very reasonable.
My plan is to save up a lot of money now.
So I can take it easy later. With that in mind,
I came up with this financial plan.
I bet you'll basically live in the cafeteria.
I had breakfast at the cafeteria.
When I have a big expense coming up, I try to cut back...
- on food. That's my first move. - Right.
Not getting delivery food would help a lot.
- Right. - One delivery fee is equivalent...
- to three meals in the cafeteria. - Right.
This was my first time taking out loans.
Since it's a large sum of money, it doesn't feel real.
But I knew I could find ways to save money.
Right. We all find ways...
- to make it work. - You'll pay it back.
It feels weird to take out a loan...
- for the 1st time. - Right. It was my 1st time.
- It makes you feel like an adult. - Right.
And pride comes into play too.
When they have to check your credit score...
- Right. - "Come on."
"Don't you read webtoons?"
I said that once when I was young.
They said they couldn't give me a big loan.
(The memory of his first loan is like a scene in a webtoon.)
- Right. - It's a pride thing.
That's right.
(He checks if the water is running just for the sake of it.)
It's clean.
(Satisfied with his clean new home)
I'm late.
(He quickly goes down to the 1st floor to get his things.)
(Rushing)
Sir.
- Get the mirror over there. - What should I grab? The mirror?
- Should I put it on there? - Yes.
- No. To the elevator. - Bring it to the elevator?
- It's not big. - This...
(They take the elevator instead of the stairs this time.)
(His things are moved quickly.)
- It must be much easier. - That's good.
We only needed a quarter of the time...
we spent before.
One.
How many trips do you think we'll need?
- About five trips. - Five?
- Five to six. - I see.
I should always live in a building with stairs.
I mean, with an elevator.
(He's clearly in love with his new home.)
Wait a moment.
Gosh, he should make good use of the elevator.
(Moving his things quickly)
I'm so grateful to the inventor of elevators.
We really should be.
The AC is on in the elevator too.
(Gratefully arriving at his unit)
One, two, three.
(Moving in his things one at a time)
It's not too hard with the elevator. Right?
Yes. It's easier with the elevator.
(Thanks to the elevator, they can move big boxes quickly.)
- One. - One, two.
There you go.
(They bring in the boxes one at a time.)
Gosh, you have so much stuff.
That was what I had after I had thrown out a lot.
(Stacking them up around the house)
(Placing Wilson down)
- We're done. - We're done.
(They're done moving the boxes at last.)
- Good job. - Thank you.
- I'll go down with you. - Okay.
(They're done moving the boxes at last.)
Having an elevator definitely helps.
- It's convenient. - It's super convenient. I love it.
How much do I owe you?
- It's 170 dollars. - It's 170 dollars.
- I brought cash. - My gosh.
(Hold on.)
Give him extra.
I'm so grateful for your help. I added 50 dollars more.
- That was nice of you. - My old place had no elevator.
You needed to give him extra. That's good.
- Thank you. - Sure.
There was no way I could have done this alone.
(Thinking about it scares him.)
- We got everything, right? - We did.
- Thank you. - Sure.
Take care.
- Bye. - Bye.
- I'll spot you. - Okay.
- Okay. Bye. - I'm so grateful to him too.
He told me to call him if I get married and have to move.
(Trudging)
There is so much stuff.
How will you live there?
(They can't believe their eyes.)
- Oh, no. - My goodness.
- What's that? - My goodness.
(Kang Yong enters his new place.)
There is so much stuff.
- Oh, no. - My goodness.
- What's that? - My goodness.
- Hey, that's... - I was so surprised.
How will you live there?
(There are four chairs...)
(and three tables.)
It's not like you need them for firewood.
Why did you leave them behind?
Lie down on the top.
(Comfortable)
I didn't know that there would be so much stuff.
(There is a lot of stuff.)
(He turns away from the piled-up items.)
(Sighing)
It's already 5:12pm.
I need to hurry.
(He hurriedly goes out without unpacking.)
(Hurried)
I turn to the left.
Seventeen minutes. Okay.
There is a convenience store nearby.
There is a laundromat too.
There is a Chinese restaurant too.
(He checks the infrastructure despite being in a hurry.)
(He arrives at a place at a fast pace.)
(Community service center?)
I wanted to get things done on my day off...
since it was open until 6pm.
To report my date of confirmation and change of address,
I went there hurriedly before it closed.
You need to do that quickly when you pay rent.
Yes, I heard that I needed to do it on the same day...
in order to secure...
- the Preferential Repayment Right. - Yes.
- I see. - It could be a rental scam.
(He gets his queue ticket and waits.)
(Ringing)
(Rushing over)
- Hello. - Hello.
- I moved in today, - Okay.
So I need to report my date of confirmation...
- and change of address. - Right.
- Please give me your ID... - Okay.
- and your contract. - Okay.
Do you need all ten pages?
That moment is a bit nerve-racking.
You feel like you've prepared something wrong.
That's right.
- Is this enough? - Yes.
- This is enough. - Okay.
(He hands over the contract he has brought.)
Please fill out the application form.
Okay.
(Change of address)
(With excitement in his heart, he writes each letter neatly.)
Will you be a resident of Yangcheon-gu?
Is it your first time moving into Yangcheon-gu?
- Yes, it's my first time. - In that case,
we give a welcome gift to people who have moved in...
- from other districts. - Really?
(I see.)
It's a thank you for moving into the district.
- Yes. - That's right.
"Please keep living here without going anywhere."
Okay.
I'll pick this gift.
(Laundry detergent is the best.)
Here you go. Thank you.
Will you add another item to the house?
You have too many items.
I picked the laundry detergent.
I thought about picking the tool set,
but I didn't want to crowd the house further.
Hey, you should've picked the tool set.
Well done.
(It's 100 percent handy.)
- The change of address is complete. - Thank you.
- Here is your new address. - Okay.
And here is your welcome gift.
Thank you.
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
Here it is.
(Feeling excited, he moves to get a copy of resident registration.)
(Happy)
Are you getting a copy for the sake of it?
I wanted to check if the change of address...
had been made successfully.
(Nervous)
(Dropping)
Address, Jungang-ro, Mok-dong, Yangcheon-gu.
- Complete. - In the morning, it was Jung-gu.
In the afternoon, it changed to Yangcheon-gu.
You're a Yangcheon-gu resident now.
What's that? They're selling fruits.
(He heads over to the store to taste Yangcheon-gu's fruits.)
Hello.
- Welcome. - Hello.
- Seon Min... - That place...
went to that vegetable place.
(A Yangcheon-gu resident, Seon Min frequents this vegetable place.)
Is it the same place?
You should go hiking with him.
- You should go to Mount Yongwang. - Yes.
Mount Yongwang.
Which refreshing fruits do you recommend?
- These days... - I live alone.
I'll take this. Yes, I'll take this.
- Apples too. - Apples.
Your total is 18 dollars.
Did you say 18 dollars? Really?
It's very cheap.
(Satisfied)
Thank you.
- I moved to a place nearby. - I see.
- Then you'll come often, right? - I'll try to come often.
- Thank you. - Bye.
Bye.
This alley has many restaurants.
Yangcheon-gu has so many good restaurants.
I think you're right.
A butchershop restaurant?
- There are so many restaurants. - He must be hungry.
I know. He had a long day.
- I didn't have a single meal. - You must be very thirsty.
I was so thirsty.
Excuse me.
Can I order three?
(Unable to fight hunger, he orders food.)
- Corndog? - I'll take six.
Okay.
They look tasty.
- They're freshly-fried. - Yes.
The freshly-fried ones are tasty.
- I'll take 0.5L of sikhye. - Okay.
I'll drink sikhye here.
All right. Thank you.
(He quickly pays.)
(Then he downs the drink.)
It must taste incredible.
(Pouring in)
Thank you.
(Guzzling)
He must've been thirsty.
My goodness. You're good at drinking.
It's bound to give him a headache.
(Getting a headache)
I knew it.
They look so tasty.
- I skipped lunch. - You must've been busy.
- Yes, I moved today. - Did you?
I moved to this neighborhood. I moved to Yangcheon-gu.
- Are you a celebrity? - Yes, I'm a celebrity.
You look familiar.
- I'm in movies. - I was in a good mood.
Actually, I'm an MBC announcer.
I should've known.
I'll come again. Thank you for the food.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
(He goes home with his hands heavy.)
- The neighborhood has nice vibes. - Yes.
(Opening)
I hate that place.
It stresses me out.
I got stressed out the most in the evening.
Anyone would get stressed out.
- Seriously. - I feel so troubled.
It'll take forever to put things away.
(It's so disorganized.)
The yellow plastic bags made it worse.
Think of it as opening the Pokemon cards.
How will I organize everything?
- Hold on. - You didn't know where to start.
That's right. I didn't know where to start.
Firstly,
let's take out...
the clothes. Let's take them out...
and put the boxes at the top.
All right.
Take out the items you need tomorrow.
- Yes. - That's right.
(He quickly hangs up clothes on hangers.)
They're all tangled up.
(But so many items remain.)
Gosh, they're heavy.
- What? - What?
Why did the light go out?
(Why did the bedroom suddenly turn dark?)
It's scary.
(It's not just the bedroom.)
He is going to die. Something is going to jump out.
(The entire house has been plunged into darkness.)
What's this?
(He comes out to the living room to figure out what's happening.)
(Flipping the switch)
- It must be a blackout. - So suddenly?
(The light doesn't come back on when he flips the switch.)
(Flustered)
It was raining.
- What's this? - What?
But rain doesn't cause a blackout, does it?
Seriously.
- What's this? - It's scary.
What's the matter?
Did the breaker trip?
Did the circus breaker trip?
- "Circus breaker?" - Unbelievable.
"Circus breaker?"
Let's retake the announcer exam.
How does one become an announcer?
You pass the exam by being like him.
(Joking)
You just need to speak nonsense from time to time.
(He was so surprised that he spoke nonsense.)
That startled me so much. "Circus breaker."
(He checks the message from the real estate agent...)
(instead of going to the circuit breaker.)
"Turning off the restroom light..."
"flips the circuit breaker at times."
- What? - The restroom light?
Why does it do that?
(Turning on the restroom light)
Where is the circuit breaker?
I had never experienced this on the day I moved in.
That's right. You didn't even use electricity.
(Is it here?)
This is a boiler room.
I couldn't find the circuit breaker.
(He can't find the circuit breaker no matter where he looks.)
- My goodness. - It's tough when that happens...
on the day you move in.
- I know. - Yes.
There is so much work to be done.
My goodness.
I'll need to call the real estate agent.
(He decides to get help from the real estate agent.)
- Hello. - Hello, ma'am.
I just moved into the house.
Okay.
The lights suddenly went off...
even though the master light switch was on.
So...
where is the circuit breaker?
The circuit breaker is behind...
the master bedroom door.
- Behind the master bedroom door? - You'll find it there. Yes.
I see. Does it trip on its own?
- Yes. I asked the landlord... - It suddenly tripped.
- to get it checked. - Okay.
- It happens sporadically. - Okay.
- I told the landlord about it. - So that was the house you chose.
- I see. - You chose well.
It's a surprise.
I got the surprise even though no one else was there.
(There was only one at the surprise party.)
You'll need to ask the landlord to get the electricity checked.
Do I ask the landlord?
- Yes, the landlord. - Okay.
- Thank you. - Take care.
(Planning an electricity checkup on the day of moving in?)
(Sighing)
(Shall I try it again?)
(Trying to turn on the light)
What?
What? Why did the lights go out?
The lights went out again.
What's going on?
- It isn't sporadic at all. - The meaning of "Sporadically..."
- The electricity bill will be low. - It happens often.
(He tries to turn the circuit breaker back on.)
This...
- What's going on? - Hey, what's wrong with it?
What's going on?
What?
It's so scary.
Oh, my.
It won't explode, will it?
Do I need to turn it on and off?
(Do I need to turn the restroom light on and off?)
- That place is too scary. - It's scary.
I can't live in such a place.
(He turns on the circuit breaker while the restroom light is on.)
Why does it do that?
(The lights turn back on.)
(Even though the lights are on...)
(Why did this happen?)
You need to figure out what the matter is.
When I turn off the restroom light, the circuit breaker trips.
- What? - What?
Once you turn it off, there is no going back.
The wires must be fused...
- with the restroom light switch. - I guess so.
Yangcheon-gu isn't an easy place.
People welcomed me, but...
- There is a hazing ritual. - Yes.
But the landlord fixed it today.
- It got fixed. - I see.
It happens. Yes.
I'm hungry. I'll need to eat dinner first.
Which menu yields the least amount of trash?
Jjajangmyeon.
You should eat jjajangmyeon on the moving day.
(He looks up nearby Chinese restaurants.)
The minimum order is 19 dollars. It's too expensive.
I can't order 19 dollars' worth of food by myself.
- It's too expensive. - The expenses will rise...
to 1,100 dollars.
(It'll happen if you try to meet the minimum order.)
The minimum order is 15 dollars.
Fifteen dollars isn't so bad.
Double portion of jjajangmyeon...
and fried dumplings.
Because of the minimum order,
I haven't ordered jjajangmyeon in a long while.
Right. Unless there are two people...
Let's put them on the bed.
(Let's resume unpacking before the food arrives.)
(He picks up the bag with clothes inside.)
(He empties it on the bed.)
Socks on the bed?
(He tosses the empty bag in front of him.)
I just need a place to sleep.
(I need a place to eat dinner.)
I have so much stuff.
(Heave-ho)
Throw away the whole thing.
Seriously, what should I do?
(He can't throw them out so he puts them on the floor.)
(I need eating utensils to have dinner.)
(Heavy)
(Grimacing, he picks up tableware.)
(It falls to the floor.)
It's hardy. It didn't break. This whiskey glass is...
definitely hardy.
(He overcomes most things with optimism.)
Had it broken, it would've been bad energy.
It didn't break, so it was good energy.
- Right. - It didn't break.
I'll put them in the overhead cabinet.
(Opening)
(Slamming shut)
What is it this time?
Why does it close on its own?
It doesn't stay open.
You didn't check a single thing.
He just went, "How nice," and moved in.
It's not like that.
"There is an elevator? How nice."
Landlords love such tenants.
(Embarrassed)
(Kang Yong, let's use your head.)
(Supporting)
- That's right. - There you go.
This place is fun.
(He supports the door with his brain.)
(I'm not sure about this.)
The cabinet door closed as soon as I opened it.
I definitely checked it before moving in.
But it seems like I should've been more thorough.
Since I checked out many places...
The last tenant left this here.
I only checked if the major components were okay...
- and didn't go further. - There are so many.
I only checked the big components, so I missed the cabinet door.
(It was my bad.)
(He takes note of the cabinet door and resumes unpacking.)
- Yes? - It's a delivery.
Thank you.
(Jjajangmyeon arrives.)
(Inching over)
(Kang Yong always ate at a floor table in the past.)
(From today onward, he'll eat at a proper table.)
Where are the chopsticks?
(Rummaging)
(He takes chopsticks out of the ziplock bag...)
(and rinses the tip with water.)
Let's eat first.
He should eat on the floor.
There is no floor.
Look at that.
(Climbing)
(He steps on the luggage to go to the table.)
(Groaning)
Gosh, this is ridiculous. This is nonsense.
The house is too cramped.
He looks rich because there is so much stuff.
Let's eat first.
(Let's eat first.)
The dumplings are hot. I love it.
- They look tasty. - They look nice.
(He takes a bite of a dumpling.)
(Gosh, it's hot.)
Gosh, I'm hungry.
(Although it's hot, he is thankful that he can eat.)
(He hurriedly mixes the jjajangmyeon.)
- The noodles aren't soggy at all. - The restaurant must be close.
Jjajangmyeon should be eaten amidst the unpacked luggage.
- You eat like that when you move. - That's right.
- That's the moving day swagger. - That's right.
You eat on the floor with the newspaper spread out.
You can only do that on the moving day.
(His first meal has the moving day swagger.)
(Slurping)
(Impressed)
This restaurant makes tasty food.
(He puts his foot on the luggage in a cool way.)
Swagger.
I had nowhere to put my foot.
(Inhaling food)
(Slurping)
- The first meal must've been tasty. - Of course.
(Salivating)
(Swinging his hand)
(Looking around)
There is no napkin.
Use your clothes.
It's in there somewhere.
(Grabbing)
(He takes off the plastic wrap from the fried dumplings.)
There you go.
No way.
(For goodness' sake)
She said it was sporadic.
I think you need to burn that gratitude journal.
That's right.
(Sighing)
(He turns on the cellphone flashlight.)
- Oh, no. - I was too hungry.
How cozy.
(Slurping)
(He eats a piece of pickled radish as well.)
You know, the lights...
What an event.
- The pattern is unpredictable. - I know.
(Getting up)
I have no strength to jump down.
(He navigates his way to turn on the lights.)
It's as if the house is alive.
The monthly rent is 1,050 dollars.
Who turns on a flashlight inside the house?
- For goodness' sake. - It lowers the electricity bill.
(It's his 3rd time looking for a circuit breaker in the dark.)
This is a serious problem.
Good.
(The house lights up again.)
Let's eat first.
I'd be too scared to live in a house like that.
- Kian84 would've gone to a motel. - I can't live in a house like that.
I find it too scary.
It's okay. This is...
how you learn.
Learn what?
(Learn what?)
You sounded like a grandpa.
- "Learn what?" - "Learn what?"
Learn what?
Just what do you learn?
(This grandpa is curious.)
When I viewed the house,
I had no idea that the lights went out often.
Right? There was no way of knowing that.
- You'll check next time. - Yes, I'll do that next time.
(He inhales the food hurriedly before the lights go out again.)
I wanted to finish eating before the lights went out again.
- Right. - It looks tasty.
I'm full.
I almost got an upset stomach.
There is so much work to be done.
(There is a mountain of bags that need to be unpacked.)
I don't think I'll be finished today.
This is bad.
(Dazed)
(Getting up)
(I must still do it.)
(Standing up)
I felt joy, sorrow, and happiness today.
I felt so happy in the morning when I packed my things.
I felt a sense of relief...
at the fact that I was moving to a bigger place.
I felt happy and wanted to leave quickly.
I felt frustrated when I arrived and brought up my things.
I missed my parents as well.
That was when I felt sorrow.
But even after that,
I imagined myself having a living room...
after sleeping in my room.
That filled me up with happiness.
There was only an entrance in a studio apartment.
But there will be a living room in a one-bedroom apartment.
I felt a lot of excitement for that.
- You'll be getting an extra room. - Right.
I'll try to get it done as soon as I can...
without overdoing it...
to get my things sorted.
After getting off work,
I will sort two bags a day.
Won't that take 1 or 2 weeks if I sort 2 bags a day?
I'll try to do that. Two bags a day.
I should hang it up there later.
The lucky broom my mom gave me.
It should go up there after bringing that down.
- Right. - Right.
How's the house right now?
Everything is sorted now.
- It took me a week. - Did you get things thrown out?
I got rid of a third of what I had.
I have a lot less now.
(It's neat now after sorting out 2 bags a day.)
(The bedroom that had no space...)
(looks quite cozy now.)
The repairman came today to fix the circuit breaker.
- Really? - That's a relief.
When you empty the house first, it can get filled with other things.
When you continue to grow and live in a bigger place,
- it will be great. - Right.
Congratulations!
(Congratulations on moving.)
(I Live Alone)
(Fathermoo)
- "Fathermoo." - "Fathermoo."
(Hyun Moo is fast asleep.)
(Groaning)
Gosh.
Gosh, Hyun Moo!
(Worried)
(He turns off the alarm while groaning.)
(Current time: 7am)
He got up so early. He wakes up so early now.
Get some more sleep!
(He wakes up with his eyes half-open.)
(Looking around)
Why does it feel like a long-term care hospital?
- Gosh. - Gosh.
Gosh, what's the point of living in a big house?
I feel pitiful, don't I?
- Oh, gosh! - I look like an old man, don't I?
- No. - It's not that bad?
- It's not that bad. - You'll recover.
I will?
(Grabbing)
(Opening wide)
Why did he wake up so early?
(He heads to the living room after picking something up.)
What? Why is it like this?
- What? - What?
(The living room is a mess?)
What's going on? Why is it like that?
(A shoe is lying around on the floor.)
- Why is one shoe there? - Look at that.
- I got so surprised. - Gosh!
Was that on top?
- It was robbed. - Gosh!
Oh, no.
You little punk!
What?
- You little punk! - It's a dog! Gosh!
- It's so cute! - It's so cute!
(I got the intruder.)
- How cute! - You little punk!
You little punk!
It's the project you've all been waiting for.
It's Part 2 of Jun Hyun Moo's 5-year good son project.
Part One was to find a place in Gimpo.
It was the project to live in a place near my parents.
(No. That can't happen!)
It was a failure.
(Failed)
Part Two...
- is this fellow. - It's so cute.
- It's a very gentle dog. - It's so small.
It's the dog my mother and father raise.
It's a mix between...
a Coton de Tulear and a Bichon Frise.
How old is it?
It's 70 days old.
- What? - It's 70 days old.
It was rescued from a puppy mill.
It's very mild and obedient.
- Kian84 made an adoption recently. - Right.
I asked him to introduce the person in charge to me.
Abandoned dog adoption and running.
(He even adopted an abandoned dog.)
You won't leave even a bit of space when you follow him.
- I copy it right away. - You copy it right away.
I'll meet Ito Junji next week.
(I'll meet Ito Junji next week.)
- Ito Junji. - I'm in trouble.
(Painting, running, dog, and Mooto Junji?)
I should've gotten married and brought them a grandchild.
This fellow is playing the role of a grandchild.
The two feel a lot of joy thanks to this dog.
It's hard for my parents to take care of things like...
the vaccination dates.
It's hard for them to reach the vet as well.
The dog was sent to me from my parents.
So you can take care of those things for them?
(He will be a good son by taking care of the dog for a day.)
You little punk!
Gosh! It's a helicopter!
Gosh!
Its fur is so cute. The grubby fur.
Was that so?
- It smells so pleasant. - Oh, right.
It's like that for all puppies.
- Is that so? - They can't get groomed now.
They must be over six months old.
They all look grubby before that.
- The expert. - Right. She's the dog expert.
Right. The dog grooming expert.
(He gets up after rubbing its grubby fur.)
(Yawning)
You punk!
(Watching)
- Gosh! - It's so cute!
It's so cute.
- Why are dogs so cute? - Gosh. Look at it...
- staying so focused already. - Let's see.
(Following)
Let's see.
Did you make a mess?
What?
- Where? No way! - Did it make a mess?
Why did you bring my shoe here?
You pooped...
I think it pooped there thinking that was the dog pad.
You little punk! I thought you were doing well.
Good job.
"Good job?"
This never happened. Why did it poop here?
You peed here well.
Why did it poop here?
It happened last night seeing how hard it is.
Did you make a mistake or not?
You little punk!
(Feeling bad)
(He heads to the bathroom to take care of the mess.)
It's a big relief that it wasn't pee.
- No way. Again? - There it goes.
It's pee this time.
(Peeing)
- I didn't know. - Pee is more troublesome.
The color of the carpet makes it harder to tell.
What happened?
- That would be hard to tell. - That would be hard to tell.
I didn't know.
(He doesn't know anything.)
(He picks up the shoe without noticing about the pee.)
How did it bring this heavy shoe?
- I wonder. - The dog must have...
- pretty strong teeth. - Right.
(Following)
It's following Hyun Moo everywhere.
Gosh, this is fascinating.
No.
No. Leave it here.
(The dog followed Hyun Moo all the way to the shoe closet.)
I should give the dog some water.
I'll give you more water.
The eyes, nose, and mouth are close to each other.
(Is that so?)
- Right. - The dog looks like Dong Yeob.
- It's so cute. - That makes it cuter.
(Pouring)
(A refill of clean water)
Water?
(Here's some water.)
Here. Have some water.
(Slurping)
(He prepares the dog food as well.)
(Peeking)
It was put in Dad's medicine bag.
A bit of milk powder was sprinkled on top.
(The dog food with milk powder gets carefully handed.)
Here. Take a look at this.
- Here's your food. - Why won't it eat?
(Sniffing)
Why won't it eat?
Puppies usually go wild when they see food.
Your food is on the plate.
(Squirming)
(Sitting)
Gosh! The dog placed its bottom on his lap!
That's so cute.
(A dad's smile)
What? Did it start to eat when the food was in your hand?
Right.
Right. Go ahead and eat.
(It starts to eat after taking a bite from his hand.)
Gosh, it's all because of you.
I was supposed to sleep in.
Did you wake up early to feed the dog?
There were set times...
- of when the dog was fed. - Right.
(Fathermoo feeds the dog after giving up on his sleep.)
- It's very gentle. - It's a quiet dog.
- It won't bark at all. - Right.
It's a nice dog.
(It's a nice dog.)
I feel so proud.
(Fathermoo feels proud to see the dog eats well.)
You're done!
- You're done! - Gosh.
How cute.
The dog must be fed at the right times.
You're done now.
(That was great.)
What should you be called?
Come here.
So the dog doesn't have a name yet.
Sunmoo? Are you Sunmoo?
Sunmoo?
Baekseolgi? Injeolmi?
It's such a cute dog.
(Thinking)
(Getting up)
(Moomoo calls someone.)
- Hello? - Hey, Dad.
Are you going to the hospital?
I won't go today.
It's my first time hearing his father's voice.
When will you be going then?
They will perform scans every three months...
to look for anything bad.
- Gosh! - Gosh!
It's so cute.
- Things are looking good for now? - Right.
He called himself a bad son,
but he's really sweet on the phone.
- It's every three months. - Do you hear his voice?
There will be an X-ray scan and a CT scan.
What's wrong?
I will be checked...
for any issues in my body.
Gosh.
Their teeth are very sharp at that age.
- Right. - They hurt so much.
What was that? Gosh, that hurt!
Every three months...
- It bites your toes, doesn't it? - Right. It bit my toe.
(Groaning)
He knew right away.
It bites at you and runs around.
That's what it does.
- Right. - Is that so?
Right.
Gosh, its teeth must feel itchy.
The dog is biting everything. Gosh!
We should name the dog.
Right.
What should we call it? I thought of Sunmoo...
as it's white.
Sunmoo is a strange name.
What do you and Mom call it?
We call it Goofball because it's a ball of trouble.
Goofball?
Should we call it Goofball?
- Goofball! - Right.
How cute!
It's full of energy.
- Okay. I'll call you again. - Right.
- Bye. - Bye.
Gosh, that hurt!
(Biting again)
It has so much energy.
Bite him.
Kill him.
(Biting)
It only bites my pinky toe.
(Oh, no!)
(Target locked on Moomoo's legs)
- Gosh, your teeth... - Does it think it's a dog chew?
It must have a nice texture.
(Laughing)
(Someone help Fathermoo!)
It has to be trained at that age...
to avoid biting in the future.
It's full of energy. What a healthy dog.
Should I call it Nonsense?
(That's too harsh.)
Nonsense!
It doesn't like that name.
Yeolmoo?
Yeolmoo!
(It's so cute.)
- Altarimoo? - Altarimoo?
He's going for names that end with Moo.
Do you like Altarimoo?
Should we go with that name?
Altarimoo!
(Ignoring)
(Thinking)
Dogs should have a childish name.
Done.
(You've decided on a name?)
You'll be called Sun Moo when you go to places like the vet.
You'll be called Goofball at home. Got it?
You're Sunmoo now.
Your nickname is Goofball. The decision has been made.
Why is it Sunmoo?
- The dog is white. - Right.
I wanted the name to end with Moo,
- but Yeolmoo is too common. - Right.
I thought of Sunmoo as soon as I saw the dog.
- Jeon Sunmoo. - Jeon Sunmoo.
(Jeon Sunmoo, 70 days old)
Come here.
Sit.
Get up.
(Lying down)
- It did the opposite. - It's so cute.
That's "down."
Come here, Sunmoo. Sit.
(Lying down)
(It's so cute.)
That's "down."
I told you to sit, ugly puppy.
- Time will fly like that. - Right.
Does Sunmoo not want to become president?
(Dalkong's brother keeps him in check.)
A dog that cute would become president.
(You're right about that.)
Get up.
(Like this!)
Sit, baby.
(Confused Sunmoo)
Paw!
You give me your paw like this.
All right. Paw!
Like this.
Paw!
(Biting)
(A bite instead of its paw)
It will only get trained when there's a reward.
It doesn't like treats yet. It doesn't eat a lot yet.
Give the dog your toe.
Your toe will be the reward.
That's what I should do.
(I must do what I can to train the dog.)
I didn't tell you to bite me.
That's "bite."
Bite!
(Bite!)
(Licking)
That's "lick."
(He's all smiles even though it gets it wrong.)
High-five! Bam!
(He doesn't give up and continues with the training.)
"Sit."
"Down."
"Up."
There you go.
(I don't like studying!)
(Thinking)
That fellow won't become president.
It's already a competition.
It will be hard to secure a top position.
(Dalkong's father is just as passionate.)
(This won't work.)
Come here! Let's go for a walk!
Let's go for a walk!
(A walk?)
Sunmoo!
Come here, Sunmoo!
You can come around, you silly thing.
Come here.
- The legs are too short. - Come around.
Oh, no!
Come here.
- Turn around. There you go. - Come here.
There you go!
How adorable.
- It's so adorable. - It's so adorable.
This phase goes by in an instant.
- Right. - Come here.
(The walk training begins in earnest.)
You have so much energy.
It's the Fun Run!
Great job. You're going to enjoy walks.
- Gosh. - The Fun Run.
The Fun Run Dog.
You have a lot of stamina.
Puppies always run around at full speed.
(The 70-day-old puppy that can run around all day)
- It keeps running. - It has great stamina.
(This man looks exhausted.)
Sunmoo! Yeolmoo!
(Fathermoo, 17,750 days old)
I've lived such a long life.
Is he some kind of wild ginseng?
- Gosh. - He's 17,750 days old.
He'll reach 20,000 days soon.
(The old father is struggling.)
(Plopping down)
Gosh, I'm exhausted.
(Exhausted)
It's the same as child-rearing.
Of course, taking care of a baby will be much harder.
It's the same when it comes to not being able to communicate.
I must take care of every part of the dog.
I believe it's a lot like taking care of a baby.
- Right. - Right.
The dog is way too young.
Everyone will say stamina is important.
But there's a good thing about being an old dad.
I'm not able to play as much as younger dads,
but I don't easily get angry after growing old.
I didn't get angry after getting bitten everywhere.
You don't have the strength to get angry.
It's because I don't have the strength.
(His generosity is because of lack of strength.)
I'm a dad who is like a great friend.
(The pride of an old father)
Sit.
Sunmoo!
(Walking away)
You're sleepy, aren't you? Your eyes are drooping down.
- Gosh! - The dog ran around a lot.
(Sunmoo becomes quiet after running around a lot.)
How cute!
It's time for a nap. Siesta.
(Let's take a nap.)
I'll turn the lights off for you. Let's sleep.
Gosh, I'm exhausted.
(For tired Sunmoo, )
(he turns out the lights.)
Come here, Sunmoo.
(Whispering)
- Come here. Let's sleep together. - It's so cute.
Let's sleep together.
(Lifting gently)
Let's enjoy the phytoncide as we sleep.
(Plopping down)
Let's sleep. I'm so sleepy right now.
(Sunmoo falls asleep quietly in Fathermoo's arms.)
How does it become so quiet all of a sudden?
- Right. - That's how babies are.
(It's just the same as child-rearing.)
It fell asleep right away.
(Fascinated)
(In case Sunmoo wakes up, )
(he stays in the same position.)
(The dog-rearing in the morning...)
(makes Fathermoo pass out.)
Gosh, Hyun Moo.
You two are just like each other when suddenly falling asleep.
- My hypnolepsy. - He fell asleep faster.
Sunmoo passed out as well.
Right. It's sleeping so well.
- Gosh! - Gosh!
It's a baby.
- Your belly must feel soft. - It's just like a water bed.
I wonder...
why this dog gets exhausted so quickly.
- Sunmoo is sleeping even now. - Is it because it's a baby?
It ran around earlier like a crazy bat.
It's knocked out now.
The dog is sleeping like an old dog.
Gosh.
It sleeps no matter how loud it gets.
I'm just like that as well.
I can sleep even when there's a fire.
I didn't wake up when there was a fire when I was in the military.
- Really? - Yes.
You guys are really similar.
The barrack was burning, but I even snored while sleeping.
Oh, my.
He's very similar to me. He's hairy too.
"He's hairy too?"
They're similar.
(Trying to find a similar trait somehow)
(The Moomoo father and son who are hairy and heavy sleepers...)
(took a nap for quite some time.)
Sunmoo. We should go for a walk.
Sunmoo.
Sunmoo?
Look at those toes.
He's sleeping soundly.
You should sleep some more. I'll go get changed.
(Fathermoo got changed first.)
I should lay down a pee pad.
(Leaving Sunmoo who is deep asleep to sleep some more, )
His food and...
(Fathermoo finishes getting thoroughly ready.)
He looks like a dad taking his daughter...
- to daycare. - He really does.
I wish I had a daughter.
(I've packed everything I needed.)
Mister.
Sir.
- Gosh. - You have to go now.
He's stretching.
- How cute. - He's so cute.
Sir.
Sir, you have to get up now.
(He's deeply asleep.)
He wouldn't wake up.
Dogs sleep a lot when they're young.
(Tiny baby Sunmoo)
(What do I do?)
Sir. Sir, get up.
Sir, get up.
You can't sleep out on the street.
Sir. Where do you live?
You can't sleep outside. Sir.
(Officer Moo tries to appease the drunk dog.)
Oh, my. Like this.
(He gets hauled away in the end.)
Like this.
(Careful)
What is this?
Look at him.
(Zoned out)
You need to get in there.
Sir.
Sir, you have to... There you go. Sir.
Are you awake now?
Sir, you have to... There you go.
- Sir. Are you awake? - He's so cute.
(Where am I?)
There, there. Goodness.
- You're so cute. You're so pretty. - Seriously...
You're so pretty.
Here we go. Shall I get you in here?
All right.
He's so small.
He's such a doll.
(Slowly moving him into the carrier so he wouldn't be startled)
Let's go somewhere fun.
He's completed all three rounds of core vaccinations.
The doctor said...
he could go for a walk...
after getting the fourth shot.
So today, he'll only get to take a sniff walk.
- A sniff walk. - A sniff walk?
Although he can't walk himself,
he has to get some fresh air...
and be outside...
so it'd help develop his social skills.
If we miss this period,
he could get intimidated...
- when he needs to take a walk... - That's right.
And avoid going for a walk.
So I decided to go to a hot spot nearby.
- A hot spot? - There's a hot spot?
(Let's go for a sniff walk, your very first in your life.)
(Taking the fancy electric bike)
- The bike looks really nice. - Let's go.
(He goes outside while struggling.)
The weather is amazing.
Sunmoo, the weather is amazing.
- The weather is so nice. - He seems to be in a good mood.
Let's go to a hot place. A hot spot.
You'll be the fastest dog to visit a hot spot after birth.
Where is it?
The neighborhood I love the most.
(The Moomoo father and son head to the mysterious hot spot.)
Now, this is a familiar view.
(Seongsu-dong)
It's Seongsu-dong.
It's the neighborhood I visit once a week, at least.
I go there because it's the mecca of pop-up stores,
and if I miss Seongsu-dong,
I'd miss Gen MZ.
So I always go there once a week on my day off.
(The center of trends he visits on his days off)
(Trend Sensitive Man has come to Seongsu-dong.)
Seongsu-dong has...
many brunch places and cafes.
There are places where dogs are welcome.
It's nice for him to get a sniff walk.
That's why I decided to go there.
(Humming)
(Staring)
Look at that.
Hello.
- Hello. - Hello.
Is this a popular place?
- Yes. - Yes. It's famous for its baguette.
Baguette?
- Should I stand in line? - You're joining the line naturally.
(Joining the line casually)
The line is considered short today.
- Really? It's usually longer? - It's way longer.
- Oh, really? - Yes.
Then I should get in line.
(Lucky!)
Gosh, I came when the line is the shortest.
Lucky me.
- Look. - He's so pretty.
He's a shelter dog.
My parents decided to take him in.
- I really wanted to see him. - Gosh.
- He felt cooped up. - Right.
Are you raising him?
No, my parents are.
Do your parents like it?
- They love it. - Really?
Of course. Gosh.
(Groaning)
Stay here for a second.
(Approaching)
- He's really cute, right? - Yes.
He's 70 days old.
Seventy days?
He's really small.
You can enter now.
Thank you.
(He hurriedly runs inside.)
It looks hip already.
Nice.
(Filled with delicious-looking bread)
It's famous for its baguette.
Baguette?
They look delicious.
(Shall I start picking them out?)
(He quickly picks them.)
- Aren't you getting too much? - Why are you getting so much?
- Can you finish them all? - You can't eat them all alone.
I picked too much.
(He even got water for Sunmoo who's waiting.)
Gosh, thank you.
Thank you.
His toes.
He must be sleepy.
(Opening the zipper)
Gosh, you must be tired.
(Fathermoo feeds Sunmoo water first.)
Aren't you thirsty?
Here, have some.
(Have a sip of water, Sunmoo.)
Gosh, he drinks when he's told to.
Gosh, you were thirsty.
You were thirsty. Gosh, it's hot. You were hot, right?
- You're doing so well. - He's so cute.
Gosh, it's refreshing.
Gosh, you were thirsty. You're so cute.
Well done.
(Kissing)
Let's go back in.
I need to eat, you see.
Go ahead and sleep.
He goes in there obediently.
(He has some bread after taking care of his dog.)
(Eating in a hurry)
This is the best.
How come no one's coming after me?
(How come no one's coming after me?)
You're right.
They definitely said people always wait in line.
- I knew it. - Soon, this place...
- will also... - I'll give you water later.
Regardless of a good baguette,
- this place will also... - A trend ender.
(It's empty now.)
Hyun Moo, pick a Pokemon card for me.
- It's in trend now, right? - Yes.
Everyone's crazy about it.
I'm keeping my eye on Pokemon cards.
They've been acting up these days.
They're acting up so much.
Goodness.
I'll leave here soon.
Let's go.
(He quickly gets going before he becomes a trend ender.)
All right. I'm sorry.
Goodness.
What is this?
What? Lasagna?
Gosh, I want to eat it, but I should hold back for Sunmoo.
(He enters the building, resisting the temptation.)
I finally got to come here.
Where is it?
What is this place?
It's a place I've had my eye on.
Hello.
A dog supply store?
(A pet supply store)
They say raising a child is a gear game.
Raising a dog is a gear game too.
There are so many things that I don't have.
I visited the place so I could get some things...
for my parents too.
Gosh, the puppy is going to have everything he needs.
What do I do? There are so many pretty things.
For a dog this size... It's 70 days old.
Is there a harness that fits his size?
(Following the staff who is guiding him)
Oh, with clothes?
- This... - He can try it on.
We have a try-on area.
- They have a try-on area? - They have a try-on area too.
Right. He should try it on.
- But that's a really good idea. - A try-on area?
There are many times when you buy your dog's clothes...
- but they don't fit. - That's right.
- They have a fitting room. - Right.
- Can he try it on? - Sure.
(Picking a harness that fits Sunmoo)
Let's go to the try-on area.
(Moving to the try-on area)
Dummy.
Here we go.
(Careful)
- No. - Make sure he doesn't fall.
Right. This is how it's put on, right?
- Yes. - You're so cute.
This must feel less tight.
He's so cute.
He's really small.
(Wagging his tail)
- You like it. - Look at him wagging his tail.
- You like it. - He looks so happy.
I should take this.
I think he'd feel less uncomfortable around the neck with this.
I'll take this one.
(He decides to get the harness right after trying it on.)
Goodness. Well done.
A carrier that's not like that...
Do you have a crossbody carrier?
So I should wear it like this?
(Hyun Moo tries it on with Sunmoo.)
- You can't get out. - It looks much more stable.
- It's way better. - It's comfortable, isn't it?
There you go. Well done.
(He decides to get the crossbody carrier right away too.)
(Super comfortable)
How cute.
These are the collaboration products we made with Sanrio.
(Collaboration products with Sanrio?)
He can't resist them.
- He can't resist. - They collaborated with Sanrio,
so you went there when they were the hottest.
I caught the trend at the very end.
You know it too.
They're almost all sold out.
Hearing her say "almost sold out" made me go crazy.
- There are only two left? - Yes.
(Handing over)
(Then I should get it.)
(Touching the last one in stock after getting the pouch)
- It's made with cooling fabric, - Cooling fabric?
So you can tell it's cool when you touch it.
- I'll get one. Yes. - This one?
(Burning with desire)
You know what drives you crazy is...
There are collaboration products not just for humans...
but for pets too.
What drives me crazy the most...
is when there are 1 or 2 pieces left on display.
"I must get that."
- "I must get that." - The central nervous system...
sends commands.
Even if I sell them at a flea market,
I must buy them first.
"You can't get them anymore. You'll never get to see them again."
And this is our best seller.
- A best seller? - Yes.
- You can't resist a best seller. - For real?
- How much is it? - Take a look.
(It's the last one in stock, on top of everything.)
- I see. - If it gets more pressed...
Oh, my. How many are you buying?
(Grabbing without hesitation)
(Throwing them into the basket)
He must love this.
It feels like watching a chaebol heir shopping.
I'll take that too.
A dog waste bag.
That one and...
and a water bowl.
- You can fill enough water. - Sounds lovely.
I'll take that and these.
(Son-loving Fathermoo's endless shopping)
I'll take this. It has multiple purposes.
(A huge pile)
Please ring them up.
(Beeping)
(Glancing)
I got so much stuff in this small store.
I see why it's important to get the right carrier.
How much is it?
It's 424.5 dollars.
- That's a lot of money. - They're really expensive.
The carrier is as expensive as a bag for people.
(Still, Fathermoo splurges for Sunmoo.)
(Hyun Moo comes out after shopping hip gear.)
What?
A line formed as soon as I left.
Hello.
So many people gathered all of a sudden?
- I mean... - It's usually like that there?
- Hello. - I mean...
there was no line when I was there. Why's there a line now?
- Hello. - Hello.
- That's a lot of people. - Enjoy.
(The line got long after Moomoo the trend ender left.)
Hello.
It's packed with people after I left.
This is incredible.
(That's strange.)
(As he's out of energy, he leaves his bike...)
(and takes taxi instead.)
- You left your bike? - Oh, right. Your bike.
- What about your bike? - Oh, because you have stuff.
- I left it there. - You'll pick it up next time?
I'll pick it up next time.
Then I should take it.
(No!)
I didn't forget.
I went to get it the next day.
(The taxi heads somewhere taking the two who are fast asleep.)
- It's correct. Yes. - This is the place.
Gosh, thank you.
(He enters a building.)
He'd realize it, wouldn't he?
There, there.
(Where are we going?)
(Hyun Moo and Sunmoo enters somewhere.)
(What is it?)
Hello.
- A reservation under Sunmoo. - Sunmoo?
Today, I went to the clinic because I made a reservation...
for the fourth round of vaccination.
It's the vet clinic Sunmoo goes to.
He got all the shots there.
Since today was a clinic day,
I planned to check...
whether he had any issues and everything else.
- Hello. - Oh, hello.
- Sunmoo is here. - Has he been well?
I bet he's got a lot bigger.
- He's gotten bigger since then. - Right?
Yes, he got bigger since the last time.
- Does he eat well? - Yes.
How do doctors remember all those?
He doesn't do that.
(Checking Sunmoo's eyes first)
You're so well-behaved.
He's really gotten bigger since the last visit.
- Right? - Yes, the puppy's gotten bigger.
I know.
- He doesn't move. - Yes. He's well-behaved.
- Other dogs go crazy, right? - Yes.
He behaved well the other time too.
He's really gentle.
I think he's patient.
Compliment him too.
He gets his ears cleaned without whining?
He's so well-behaved.
He doesn't even whimper.
(Smiling from ear to ear)
Let's check his temperature,
and if he's fine, I'll give him a shot.
- Today's is... - It's the fourth round.
After getting a shot today, he can go for short walks.
- He can go outside? - Yes, he can.
- With a harness? - Yes, I think he can go out.
Why can't he go for a walk right away?
- In case he gets infected. - Right.
- Outside... - Because vaccinations aren't done.
Because they're weak.
(Getting the sharp needle ready)
A shot?
- They don't like it. - Let's see...
- They don't. - if you take it well. Hold still.
He did take it well last time.
(Worried)
(The needle gets close.)
Gosh, he's so tiny. It must hurt.
There you go.
This will sting a little.
(Will Sunmoo be okay?)
(Pressing hard)
- I couldn't watch. - It's scary to watch.
This will sting a little.
- You did well. - What a good boy.
- He's... - Gosh.
He's quiet.
What a good boy.
(Calm)
I think...
he's really gentle.
It's not that he's gentle.
- Maybe he doesn't feel it? - He's so gentle.
(He's calm even after getting the second shot.)
Oh, my.
(Sunmoo has no problem getting shots.)
How can he not make any noise?
- Maybe he doesn't feel it? - Good boy.
(The puppy doesn't even cry and gets shots well.)
He's unfazed.
He's okay, right?
Of course. He's so...
- He's not affected at all? - Right?
There aren't many dogs who don't feel pain...
- after getting shots. - I know.
- Right? They whine, right? - Yes.
It's because he's gentle in nature.
- I see. - He's so cute.
He's like a miracle.
He's worth studying.
He's a case where a veterinary paper could be written about.
The thesis topic is, "What's Wrong With Sunmoo?"
Even dogs who are patient...
blink a little when the needle goes in.
Or do this.
He didn't flinch at all.
The needle was quite big too.
(He calmly took the shots.)
This is all he did.
He'll become a great figure.
He'll become something.
- Now we can take a walk. - Yes, you can.
- I can walk him on a harness. - Yes.
- He can shower once in two weeks. - Yes.
Do I not need to change his food?
When can he be neutered?
He can be neutered when he's around 5 to 7 months.
After all his vaccination shots...
- After everything is done? - Yes, when they're done.
We'll book his neutering around that time.
All right. There aren't more things I should take note of, right?
No. I think he'll be fine.
- You can wash him a day after. - All right.
- Thank you. - Sure.
- I'll see you in two weeks. - Look at him going to Hyun Moo.
He's so cute.
He felt stuffed when I put him in a backpack.
- Thank you. - Sure. Thank you.
- I'll see you in two weeks. - All right.
(Veterinary Clinic)
You're a good boy.
Gosh, well done, Sunmoo.
Fathermoo is back.
(Packed with things)
Gosh, they're so heavy.
- He really bought a lot. - He bought so much.
Here. There you go.
Have fun.
(I'm home!)
Goodness.
Gosh, I'm so tired.
(Staring)
Why did I get so much stuff?
(He starts unpacking as soon as he gets home.)
I did buy a lot.
I don't think you can tell what's what.
(He takes out the things he splurged on today.)
That's the thing you got.
The popular item.
Some dogs are scared of toys like that.
Please like it.
(Will he like it?)
- He's showing interest. - Right.
I did well getting that.
(Impressed)
You're attacking it.
- Look at you. - Oh, my.
Oh, my.
- He has a lot of strength. - He's strong.
(Fearless dog)
He took the shots with no problem. That's not a big deal.
- It's heavy. - He's fearless.
- He's not scared. - Look at you.
(Biting)
He's shaking.
(Shaking)
It's almost like mixed martial arts.
(I never let go of a turtle once I bite it.)
He loves it.
I did well by getting a moving toy.
It was money well spent.
Sunmoo, come here. Let's try on the dog tank top.
Dog tank top?
Come on.
Gosh, good boy.
- He's so cute. - He's calm when wearing clothes.
- Many dogs hate it too. - That's right.
(Gentle)
Oh, my. It suits him so well.
It must feel rewarding to get him clothes.
It looks good on you. It's pretty.
That was a good buy.
It was a good buy. I'm super happy.
Let me...
Gosh, this is so comfortable.
(Drained)
(He gets up right away even while resting.)
(Passing out after taking care of his dog all day)
It's really tiring.
He's a blessing.
My parents often go to the hospital,
so there isn't much for them to smile about.
But they do smile a lot these days.
They'd go, "My dear Goofball."
My father goes for dialysis three times a week.
(His father has dialysis three times a week.)
There must be no joy even when they come back home.
Their son isn't married...
and is only getting old. They wouldn't be happy.
But thanks to him, they became really happy.
They don't call or text me unless they want to...
nag at me about having meals or putting on socks.
But now, regardless of nagging,
they'd send photos of him.
"He ate well today too."
This one really is a good son project.
- Do you approve of this? - Yes, I do approve of it.
Now, he only has to give them a peck on the cheek.
I realized they were really happy.
I did well by bringing him.
It's the finale of the five-year good son project.
What? That's it?
- It's the end. - Isn't it too fast?
The end.
(Sunmoo, be a good son for my sake too.)
Sunmoo, you'll have to do all the job.
There are so many things Sunmoo can do...
to be a good son instead of me.
(The End of the 5-year Good Son Project)
(The End of the 5-year Good Son Project?)
(Next story)
(She showed a good performance as the competent eldest daughter...)
(on "Reply 1988.")
(A scene-stealer full of charisma)
(It's been 11 years since she started living alone.)
(It's Actress Ryu Hye Young.)
(In every corner of her dark house, )
(there lie Hye Young's charming pieces.)
(Hye Young wakes up in a pitch-dark room.)
(Peeking)
(Get some sunlight.)
(She only allows a ray of sunlight to her plant friend.)
(In the corner of a dark living room, )
(she fiddles around.)
(I'm a timid person who's easily scared.)
(I just saw you, Wilson.)
(You're a scary one, aren't you?)
(I used to feel insecure about myself.)
(But why must I hide?)
(World, here I come.)
Let's just do it.
(Here comes Ryu Hye Young!)
(I'm quite fast today.)
(Taking little steps)
(I'm going past you.)
(Don't worry too much about what others think.)
(Things she learned after a long journey of time)
- This is nice. - At my own pace...
(I just need to go at my own pace.)
(This is great!)
(Taking little steps)
(At My Own Pace)
(CODE KUNST who always takes things easy)
(He goes on a miracle morning?)
(It's the day of the match between South Korea and Czechia.)
(The Rainbow Club's official soccer maniac, CODE KUNST)
(Is this...)
(the coach's point of view?)
(They got it.)
(Legendary couch coach)
(Our team is dominant.)
(What about the simulation?)
(He's been waiting for this day for 4 years.)
(Waiting to cheer in all red)
(Here comes the Red Devil CODE KUNST.)
(Welcoming the Red Devil CODE KUNST...)
(are the members of Epik High.)
(Can't we eat fried chicken?)
(No!)
(Let's just eat. You can treat us something else after it too.)
(Please...)
(You guys are unstoppable.)
- Right after the kick-off... - It's starting!
(The match has started.)
(Getting excited from the start)
(He pushed Kang In? I can't hold back!)
(Let's play well!)
(Going through...)
(extreme highs and lows)
(We'll Cheer for Team Korea)